Mai Le

Master of Data Science, University of British Columbia

Mai Le has 14 years of experience in the software industry, more than 10 years in project management and 4 years in executive role. She is enthusiastic in building organization culture, managing large-scale projects and is fascinated with people development.

Mai is now embarking a new journey in Data Science to enable greater contribution to her future organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

KMS Technology, Vietnam — *Vice President of Delivery*

JUNE 2018 - FEBRUARY 2020

Manage a Business Unit of 150-200 software developers and testers, providing consultancy advice on software development processes and supplementing engineering effort to implement product roadmap for US software companies

KMS Technology, Vietnam — Director of Delivery

APRIL 2016 - JUNE 2018

Planned and executed multiple highly complex software development projects in parallel

Home, Vietnam — *Maternity Leave*

APRIL 2015 - APRIL 2016

KMS Technology, Vietnam — Senior Engineering Manager

JANUARY 2013 - APRIL 2015

Planned and executed multiple software development projects

KMS Technology, Vietnam — Engineering Manager

SEPTEMBER 2010 - JANUARY 2013

Managed Customer Support team for an e-commerce solution provider

Catglobe, Vietnam — Production Manager

NOVEMBER 2008 - AUGUST 2010

Led a team of data consultants in implementing and customizing CRM systems

815/36 Ta Quang Buu, Ward 5, District 8, Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

+84 918449010

lephanthuymai@gmail.com

SKILLS

Data Science
Business Administration
Software Project Management
Software Development

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C#, Java, Javascript, Python, R

AWARDS

Gold Medal - Graduated with Highest Honor, Ho Chi Minh City - University of Technology

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (Native), English (Fluent)

Catglobe, Vietnam — *Team Leader*

OCTOBER 2007 - NOVEMBER 2008

Led a team of 5 developers and testers to develop features of a CRM system

Catglobe, Vietnam — Senior Developer

JANUARY 2007 - OCTOBER 2007

Designed and implemented complex modules of a CRM system

Catglobe, Vietnam — *Developer*

APRIL 2006 - JANUARY 2007

Designed and implemented modules of a CRM system

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, Canada – *Master of Data Science*

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

Vietnam National University, Ho Chi Minh - University of Technology, Vietnam — Bachelor of Engineering, Gold Medal (summa cum laude equivalent), Computer Science & Engineering

SEPTEMBER 2001 - MARCH 2006